Stanislav Starishko

Glasgow, UK, G72 8PG | WhatsApp/Tel: 07387914778 | Email: starishko.s@gmail.com

Web: https://github.com/StanStarishko/Portfolio | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/starishko/

Permit: Category B | Legally authorized to work in the UK

Summary:

Motivated results-driven professional with years of experience, recognised for assessing operational needs, and developing solutions to save costs, improve revenues and drive customer satisfaction. Resourceful, well-organised with excellent leadership and team-building record. Passionate Developer with experience in data accuracy, management. Independent problem-solver focused on customer service, product development. Works well under tight deadlines.

Technical Skills:

- Programming Languages: 1C (akin to Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics, SalesForce), T-SQL, R, Java (Collections, Lambda Expressions), Python (Flask, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Lambda Expressions), JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Turbo Pascal, Delphi, C, C++
- Development Tools & Environments: Delivering complex (ERP) enterprise level systems, Writing secure and high-quality code, Full Life Cycle and Decisions Architecture, Object-Oriented (OOP), Modular Programming, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), MVC, SOLID, QA MT/AT, Unit Testing, Test Driven Development (TDD), BDD, Design of architecture IT products, services and solutions, AWS, Lambda, S3, APIs, Jira, Trello, Data and system analyst
- Databases: MSSQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite
- Methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Kanban, Waterfall, and Time, Team, Product, Project, and Crisis Management

Key Skills:

- Enthusiastic up for challenge
- Analytical and Outside The Box Thinking
 Crisis Resolution
- Excellent Team Collaboration
- Passionate about software
- Attention to Detail
- Team Productivity Enhancement
- Business Process Understanding
- Process Modernization

Work History:

Glasgow Film Theatre

08/2023 - Current

Tashkent, Uzbekistan

Volunteer-Customer Assistant

Glasgow, UK

- Oversaw daily operations involving more than 50 customer interactions, ticket validation, and postperformance cleanup for optimal customer experience
- Provided exceptional customer service, promptly addressing queries and offering product recommendations to enhance shopping experience

EVOS Good Food 09/2021 - 02/2022

- **Director of Digital Transformation**
 - Enforced innovative timekeeping facial recognition in ERP rise 80% HR processes within just 2.5 months
 - Implemented measures to stop the growth of technological debt in just two months

Established ERP systems increased accounting and finance productivity by 30%

Freelance 11/2019 - 08/2021 **Software Engineer Dnipro, Ukraine**

- Developed software modules to improve financial reporting speed to 25%
- Enhanced software components by troubleshooting and modifying code

EVA Retail 10/2018 - 11/2019

Head Software Department

Dnipro, Ukraine

- Incorporated cutting-edge techniques like SBS feedback, hybrid Agile, Scrum, CorpScrum, Prince2, Waterfall approach leading to a notable 20% boost in team efficiency
- Effectively managed 10+ projects, each lasting 1-3 years, played pivotal role in creation payment calendar
- Executed 20+ short-term projects, each lasting up to 6 months, consistently meeting all deadlines
- Developed strategy plan to enhance support software for 900+ retail outlets and 3500+ users, achieving business efficiency improvement 10%
- Successfully roll out sophisticated ERP caused impressive 10% rise accounting finance department productivity
- Implemented strategy effectively halted company's technological debt growth within just 4 months

Re-entry from Junior 1C8 Developer to Head of Software Department

- Dnipro, Ukraine
- Solved problems in 280 1C databases on MSSQL, reduced update time by 98%, from 2.5 months to 3-5 days
- Achieved impressive 80% enhancement support efficiency establishment by transformation initiative
- Exhibited phenomenal efficiency surpassing projected 8-months milestones within just 2 weeks
- Significantly reduced exchange time by 99.5% from 8-14 hours to 2-5 minutes by implemented high-speed data synchronization for 1C (similar to Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics, SalesForce)
- Implemented seamless execution comprehensive automation plan for manufacturing within ambitious 10month timeline

Company Adeon Franchising 1C

02/2007 - 03/2014

Dnipro, Ukraine

• Delivered 12+ long-term projects, each completed under budget within specified timelines of 8 to 18 months by1C technology (akin to Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics and SalesForce)

Retail and Logistic Companies

10/1991 – 02/2007

Software Developer

Co-owner/CEO

Dnipro, Ukraine

- In 2003, rapid effectively, for one month, retrained to 1C developer (akin to Java, Python, C#, C, C++, Dynamics, SalesForce)
- Established proficiency in Turbo Pascal, Delphi, C, C++, showcasing decade software development excellence from 1991-2003

Education and Training:

PDA Cyber Resilience	SCQF8	Code Division, futureCoders	UK	11/2023 - 03/2024
Cyber Engineers	CyberOps Associate	Cisco Networking Academy	UK	11/2023 - 03/2024
PDA Software Development	SCQF7	Glasgow Clyde College	UK	08/2023 - 11/2023
NPA Software Development	SCQF6	Glasgow Clyde College	UK	04/2023 - 07/2023
NQ Access to Business Administration, Accounting and IT	SCQF4	Glasgow Clyde College	UK	01/2023 - 06/2023
Python	Fundamental	DataCamp	USA	11/2022 - 03/2023
New strategic thinking. Selection Management	Advanced	EVA Academy, Arkadiy Tsuker	Ukraine	05/2019 - 05/2019
Project Management by Agile, Scrum and Kanban	Advanced	EVA Academy	Ukraine	11/2018 - 04/2019
Corporate course of business changes and transformation	МВА	Institute of Adizes, Ukrainian Office	USA	02/2018 - 09/2018
Programming for Computing Devices and Automated Systems	BTEC, SCQF7	Automation and Telemechan College	Ukraine	09/1990 - 03/1993

Languages: English - Intermediate, Ukrainian – Native, Russian - Native

Hobbies & Interests: Traveling, exploring new technologies, personal development